it's an 18% core Roe which is just a
fantastic way for us to express uh
Express the quality of our franchise the
biggest Improvement is going to come
from our Asian and gwm businesses gwm is
our asset management and wealth business
and that's in part driven by some of the
great demographic Trends we see in Asia
and so we've got low insurance
penetration rates so that should drive
further growth and also we're building
scale in many markets you mentioned
Jakarta and Indonesia great a great
example of a market that once we build
scale we're going to see some fantastic
profitability come through that's going
to DW the group are we up so very
exciting targets and we think another
great step in our journey of
transformation in a recent months you
guys announced some reinsurance deals uh
you completed the largest long-term care
insurance reinsurance deal in history
this has freed up capital for share
BuyBacks uh what is the impact to
earnings because in my reading some
analysts are taking note that the
reinsurance strategy does not appear to
have unduly weighed on core earnings has
it weighed on earnings at all yes that's
a great Point actually and you know you
mentioned the two transactions we did
the one in December acted as a real
Catalyst for our share price um and we
we transacted with global Atlantic and
we transacted on a $6 billion of
long-term care reserves now sure that
did reduce earnings a little bit but
what it did is it freed up Capital by
more and allowed us to buy back stock
and so our earnings per share actually
went up and our core Roe went up as a
result so that's all in line with our
strategy of getting to an 18% core Roe
company now Asia is important a market
for you guys it makes up about 37% of
your core earnings you've pushed back to
2027 by 2 years for the Asia unit to get
to 50% now the P pandemic of course is
part to blame for everything and uh but
how much of it has to do with some of
the patchiness in terms of an economic
recovery we're seeing from China yeah
it's you know there were two items
associated with the push back in our
Target the first was sure the the the
recovery from the pandemic took a little
was a little bit more uneven than we
expected but also we had a big
accounting change and so that impacted
if7 did impact some of the earnings
emergence from our Asian region these
two factors did make us pause and push
our Target out to 2027 but I will say
that at the q1 stage uh we were 44% of
our earnings came from Asia so we
showing good progress from the full year
number that you quoted and uh you know
if you think about the demographic
Tailwinds that are going to push growth
in this region we're very comfortable
with the 2027 and excited about the
region as a whole really in the region
here you Service 13 markets I believe
generating or I should say servicing 13
million customers this region has been
an area of strength what is the outlook
for Asia we you know we there's a reason
why we're bringing investors from all
over the world to come and see us here
in Hong Kong you know just fantastic
energy in the business fantastic
momentum in the business and you know
you mentioned the the economic
environment we sell peace of mind so
sometimes G Glo Global macroeconomic
developments don't necessarily Drive
insurance sales and and we're able to be
that that company that's always going to
be here with a great brand we've got a
great products uh product set and so
it's just the demographic Tailwinds that
have been in place for many years
continue to be in place and we we just
want to take advantage of that and also
showcase it we're looking at some other
companies double down in the region you
guys have invested into maau uh you're
expanding there the population is on10th
of Hong Kong but I believe the
penetration of insurance is only half of
what we're seeing in Hong Kong what are
you doing here in this city in MAA to
further expand in the greater Bay Area
yeah so maau we've just got new offices
so fantastic uh presence for manual life
from maau one of the 11 greater Bay Area
cities so again fantastic opportunity to
meet uh visitors coming over from the
mainland to see our product Suite we've
got a great range of products and be it
savings protection retirement Health um
and we seen great momentum in sales in
that region so maau is smaller than Hong
Kong but the greater Bay Area as a whole
has as you mentioned much lower
Insurance penetration than Hong Kong so
another Tailwind to
growth the largest insurer in Canada
Bank of Canada recently cut rates so
they've started their rate cutting cycle
what are the risks and the impact to
your profitability yeah you're right we
had a quarter point rate in uh reduction
in the early June and actually our
economists think there's probably going
to be another three more in 2024 and
More in 2025 now the good news for
manual life is that actually we're more
susceptible we're more sensitive to the
longer end of the curve and the longer
end of the curve has stayed more
resilient but at the same time we don't
take big interest rate risk we know we
look to try and make we look to make our
money from underwriting and selling
great Health Products and so we're less
focused on what where the rate interest
the interest rate movements may move
from here but at the same time
short-term interest rates not a big deal
for manual life you guys are engaged in
share BuyBacks uh tell us in terms
update us on your Capital reserves and
how much do you intend to return to
shareholders yeah you know we've got $22
billion of capital in excess of our
regulatory minimum and we wouldn't go
down to Bare Bones on the regulatory
minimum so we consider having our
Capital base to be around $10 billion of
excess above what we call our upper
operating limit so our most important
use for our capital is to invest in our
own business because we know it so well
and it's it's generating great returns
so that's why we're here in Asia is we
we're showing people where we're
allocating Capital too our second most
important use for our capital is
dividend growth we've got a earnings per
share growth uh Target of 10 to 12% and
if we're paying out 35 to 45% in
dividends you can see a really good
dividend trajectory and then the third
item is is whether we do m&a or share
BuyBacks and so far share BuyBacks have
generated $3 billion of value based on
the current share price so that's been
an attractive lever for us but we'll
continue to look at external
opportunities but we can be incredibly
disciplined when it comes to external
opportunities